<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts</title>
    <description>A personal blog site for me, with musings about technology and documenting what I learn.
</description>
    <link>http://www.hywel.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.hywel.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 14:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 14:41:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title> Moving a WordPress site from GoDaddy to DigitalOcean - Part 1 Why?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It it time for a change.  I had a great deal for a 5 year ultimate hosting plan with free SSL at &lt;a href=&quot;http://GoDaddy.com&quot;&gt;GoDaddy.com&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, now they want to charge me an arm and a leg to renew - GoDaddy provides a great price for new customers, but charge &lt;strong&gt;alot&lt;/strong&gt; when you are locked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the response time for all the websites hosted with them has not been good enough - especially now that Solid State Disks (SSDs) are becoming more commonplace with hosting companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have decided try out the &lt;em&gt;do it yourself&lt;/em&gt; cloud hosting option provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=92e12787bf7a&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean.com&lt;/a&gt; partly to learn some new skills and also they have had some great reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick search online, I found a promotional code to get 2 months free hosting with DigitalOcean.com, so at least I could try before I buy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member, DigitalOcean offer a referal scheme - please click my link if you’d like to try it for free:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=92e12787bf7a&quot;&gt;$10 credit at Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DigitalOcean’s documentation and user forums are very active and I found it quite straight forward as a tech-savvy person to get a basic Ubuntu operating system insalled on a &lt;em&gt;droplet&lt;/em&gt; . &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DigitalOcean is managed through a command line terminal, so if you are slightly allergic to the thought of typing commands, it’s propably not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serverpilot.io/?refcode=c2131f64db72&quot;&gt;Serverpilot.io&lt;/a&gt; is a simple  management system for DigitalOcean servers. Even their free plan takes care automatically of basic server security and PHP application management.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.serverpilot.io/?refcode=c2131f64db72&quot;&gt;$10 credit at ServerPilot.io&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also tempted with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com&quot;&gt;CloudFlare.com&lt;/a&gt; service as it offers free SSL/ SDPY and static file cache - which is supposed to translate to faster and more Google friendly websites. Worth a try right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next post, I’ll describe the steps to move the WordPress site to DigitalOcean using ServerPilot.io and then, hopefully CloudFlare!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.hywel.me/digitalocean/wordpress/2015/03/05/moving-wordpress-from-godaddy-to-digitalocean-and-cloudflare-part1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hywel.me/digitalocean/wordpress/2015/03/05/moving-wordpress-from-godaddy-to-digitalocean-and-cloudflare-part1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalocean</category>
        
        <category>wordpress</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 19:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.hywel.me/jekyll/update/2015/03/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hywel.me/jekyll/update/2015/03/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
